

RYAN ROSS

Sales & Customer Service

Walnut Creek, CA

Rossryan1990@gmail.com

+15103670989

Sales expert with extensive experience in solution based consultancy and prime customer service.

Experience in retail environment and excellent communication skills due to high proficiency in literature, writing and critical thinking.

Ability to work efficiently with a team or solo, while being aware of time constraints and deadlines.

Relevant Knowledge, Skills, and Training

Sales • Customer Service • Leadership • Order processing • Procurement • Inventory control • Communications • IT • Cash Handling • Blockchain Technology

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

WORK EXPERIENCE

Sales Representative

Dolans Lumber - Walnut Creek, CA

August 2018 to Present

B2B Sales, B2C Sales, Customer support, order processing, backup IT support, and communications are a large part of this sales role. Primarily sell construction products, including wood and hardware to contractors, construction business owners, and walk-in home owners.

Minor role in solution based consultancy assisting customers on all the options for their projects in order for them to get the best outcome . This can involve special ordering materials to fit their specific needs.

Sales Representative

MacBeath Hardwood Company - Berkeley, CA

July 2013 to August 2018

Customer support, order processing, fulfillment, transfers, and communications are the main responsibilities of this sales position. Moved to a solution based consultancy type of

role as a result of my ability to learn and retain relevant information quickly and advise customers about the products available and what would suit their needs.

Previously, I worked as a warehouse clerk and was responsible for receiving and stocking

merchandise, making sure the machinery is serviced and functional, fulfilling customers orders, maintain records of all activities and processes concerning the warehouse.

IT Support for Resnet, UC Santa Cruz

University of California, Santa Cruz - Santa Cruz, CA

September 2011 to October 2011

Helped set up internet connections in dorms/student quarters. Performed virus scans, did removals of malware and system reformatting. Wrote summaries of work tickets for computers brought in for repairs and updates. Coordinated work to be done and saw that jobs were completed on schedule and ready as promised.

Internship as Inventory Technician

CoolSystems, Inc - Berkeley, CA June 2007 to August 2007

As an Inventory and Service Technician, I was trained to help pull sales orders, pack them and prepare for shipment to customers. I also performed some of the final mechanical assembly of the main control units the company made. Incoming inspection required considerable time

demands from the QA Engineer, so I helped inspect and test new shipments of components and finished goods. I was able to put my eye for detail and mechanical skills to good use in this position.

Additional Information

Clubs and Societies - Youth Commission - Volunteered on event planning and fund raising for the Pinole community.

EDUCATION

Bachelor in English Literature

University of California - Santa Cruz, CA June 2013

SKILLS

- MICROSOFT OFFICE (2 years)
- OUTLOOK (1 year)
- Customer Service (6 years)
- Sales Experience (6 years)
- Blockchain (2 years)

LINKS

CERTIFICATIONS AND LICENSES

Blockchain Technologies: Business Innovation and Application

June 2018 to Present

Acquired knowledge about blockchain technology, its functionality, purpose and potential uses for present and future applications. Main focuses were business innovations and how the technology could improve business workflow and functionality.

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Technologies: Microsoft Office Suite, All Internet Browsers, Outlook, Google Suite.